Guide to the Charles Parr Burney, Correspondence
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
[Correspondence]
1819-1857
OSBORN D149
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.04
(1 volume)
Autograph MSS. Collection of letters and papers relating to the establishment of the Porson and Burney Prizes at Cambridge University [Richard Porson (1759-1808)].
Burney, Charles P. (Charles Parr), 1785-1864
Immediate Source of Acquisition
For provenance information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The following finding aid is a partial inventory of the contents of Osborn d149. This list was reformatted from previously existing cataloging.
Women authors; Burney, Charles P. (Charles Parr), 1785-1864
- Osborn d149
  - BASS, THOMAS BAKER
    - ALS to Charles Parr Burney (1785-1864), 1848 Feb 22 (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Dover
      1 p.; 22 x 19 cm.
      Returns a check he has been sent as
      his fees had been paid by the
      solicitors, Clark & Davidson.
      d149/39
  - BURNEY, CHARLES PARR, 1785-1864
    - ALS (draft) to Clark & Davidson, solicitors, 1848 Jan 26 (Box 1)
      Sible Hedingham
      1 p.; 18 x 11 cm.
      Concerns accounts of the Porson
      Prize; send a copy of the letter to
      Child and Co.
      d 148/40a
    - AL (copy) to Child and Co. (Box 1)
      Introduces the firm Clark and Davidson
      concerning the Porson Prize.
      d 149/40b
    - AL (draft) to "Notes and Queries" (Box 1)
      1 p.; 15 x 11 cm.
      Extends authorization to the editor
      of "Notes and Queries" to state the
      foundation of the Porson Scholarship
      and its finances.
      d 149/43
    - AL (draft) to Henry Philpott, bp. of Worcester (1807-1892), 1846 Dec 31 (Box 1)
      [Sible Hedingham]
      2 p.; 18 x 11 cm.
      Response to a letter he had received
      from Philpott concerning the "Burney
      Prize."
      d 149/23
    - ALS (draft, incomplete) to Henry Philpott, bp. of Worcester (1807-1892), [1847] (Box 1)
      1 p.; 19 x 11 cm.
      Part of a note of contribution.
      d 149/30
    - ALS (draft) to Henry Philpott, bp. of Worcester (1807-1892) (Box 1)
      3 p.; 18 x 12 cm.
      Concerns the bishop's contribution.
      d 149/26
    - ALS (draft) to Henry Philpott, bp. of Worcester (1807-1892), 1847 May 17 (Box 1)
      1 p.; 21 x 17 cm.
      Concerns the regulations of the
      Porson Prize.
      d 149/32
    - ALS (draft) to Henry Philpott, bp. of Worcester (1807-1892), 1847 Oct 19 (Box 1)
      1 p.; 19 x 12 cm.
      Concerns the Porson Scholarship and
      recent proposals made by the bishop.
      d 149/34
    - ALS (draft) to Ralph Tatham (1779-1857), 1846 Jun 26 (Box 1)
      Concerns the reaction to the Porson
      Prize by some Heads of Colleges at
      Cambridge University.
      d 149/13
    - ALS (draft) to Ralph Tatham (1779-1857), 1845 Jul 4 (Box 1)
      1 p.; 20 x 12 cm.
      Thanks him for his attention and
      service to the Porson Prize.
      d 149/15
    - ALS (draft) to Ralph Tatham (1779-1857), 1845 Oct 28 (Box 1)
      1 p.; 19 x 15 cm.
      Concerns the procedure for bringing
      the Porson Scholarship to the
      attention of the proper University
      authorities.
      d 149/16
    - ALS (draft) to John Haggard (1794-1856), 1845 May 29 (Box 1)
      Concerns a conference they had on
      the admission of churchwardens.
      d 149/17
  - BURNEY, JANE CAROLINE
    - ALS to Charles Parr Burney (1785-1864) (Box 1)
      n.p.
      Sends along something for his
      perusal.
      d 149/14
  - CAMBRIDGE UNIVERSITY. ST. JOHN'S COLLEGE
    - [Graces offered to the Senate]: printed notice with MS annotations, 1846 Jun 9 (Box 1)
      1 p.; 24 x 22 cm.
      Includes proposals by Charles Parr
      Burney (1785-1864) for the
      establishment for a Porson Prize and
      by Miss J. Caroline Burney for the
      establishment of a Burney Prize.
      d 149/8
  - CHANTREY, SIR FRANCIS LEGATT, 1781-1841
    - Invoice to Charles Parr Burney (1785-1864), 1819 Jul 9 (Box 1)
      Belgrave Place
      1 p.; 15 x 20 cm.
      Regarding a bust of Porson with a
      tablet; with an autograph receipt
      attached.
      d 149/1
  - CLARK, H. M.
    - ALS to Charles Parr Burney (1785-1864) (Box 1)
      London
      1 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
      Has received the draft by Henry
      Philpott, bp. of Worcester
      (1807-1892), concerning the
      establishment of the Porson Prize.
      d 149/36
  - CLARK AND DAVIDSON, SOLICITORS
    - ALS to Charles Parr Burney (1785-1864) (Box 1)
      A bill for their services concerning
      the principal and interest of the
      money to be used for the
      d 149/38
  - HANBURY, AGATHA
    - ALS to Charles Parr Burney (1785-1864) (Box 1)
      Poles
      Letter which accompanied her annual
      donation to the Hedingham Schools.
      d 149/24
  - PHILPOTT, HENRY, BP. OF WORCESTER, 1807-1892
    - ALS to Charles Parr Burney (1785-1864), 1846 Dec 5 (Box 1)
      Cambridge
      5 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
      Concerns the establishment of the
      Porson Prize as well as J. Caroline
      Burney's recent alterations in her
      wishes concerning the administration
      of the Burney Prize.
      d 149/21
    - ALS to Charles Parr Burney (1785-1864) (Box 1)
      3 p.; 18 x 11 cm.
      Concerns J. Caroline Burney's
      proposals regarding the Burney Prize.
      d 149/22
    - ALS (copy) to Clark & Davidson, solicitors, 1848 Jan 13 (Box 1)
      Sends the draught of the Deed of
      Trust for the foundation of the
      Porson Scholarship.
  - TATHAM, RALPH, 1779-1857
    - Memorandum: autograph MS (Box 1)
      3 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
      On the reasons for objecting to the
      establishment of the Porson Prize
      proposed by Charles Parr Burney
      (1785-1864).
      d 149/9
    - ALS to Charles Parr Burney (1785-1864) (Box 1)
      2 p.; 25 x 20 cm.
      Thanks him for his offer to
      establish a prize fund.
      d 149/3
    - ALS to Charles Parr Burney (1785-1864) (Box 1)
      Informs him that his proposals for
      the establishment of the Porson
      Prize have been submitted to the
      Heads of Colleges.
      d 149/4
    - ALS to Charles Parr Burney (1785-1864) (Box 1)
      Concerns a proposed substitution in
      the rules for the Porson Prize.
      d 149/5
    - ALS to Charles Parr Burney (1785-1864) (Box 1)
      3 p.; 20 x 12 cm.
      Concerns a new draft of the Porson
      Prize.
      d 149/6
    - ALS to Charles Parr Burney (1785-1864) (Box 1)
      4 p.; 25 x 20 cm.
      Concerns the proposal for a Burney
      d 149/7
    - ALS to Charles Parr Burney (1785-1864) (Box 1)
      Informs him that the matter of the
      Porson Prize has finally been
      settled.
      d 149/12
    - ALS to Charles Parr Burney (1785-1864) (Box 1)
      Concerns the deferral of the Porson
      Scholarship.
      d 149/18
    - ALS to Charles Parr Burney (1785-1864) (Box 1)
      Concerns the Deed of Trust for the
      Burney Prize.
      d 149/19
    - ALS to Charles Parr Burney (1785-1864) (Box 1)
      Concerns the deed for the Burney
      Prize to be established by J.
      Caroline Burney.
      d 149/20
  - WILLIAMS, ROWLAND, 1817-1870
    - ALS to Charles Parr Burney (1785-1864) (Box 1)
      8 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
      Objections to the form of the
      proposed establishment of the Porson
      d 149/10